Jack T. Nugent

Richmond, VA | 2: 804.833.6200 | : jacknugent27@gmail.com | : jacknugent.io

PROFILE SUMMARY

Intelligent and highly motivated Full Stack Developer with over three years professional experience in Frontend, UI, Object Oriented Analysis, Design, Development, Configuration, Testing, Support, and Documentation in the entire stage of Software Development Life Cycle and System Architecture. Proficient at implementing core backend development tasks including 3rd party API integrations, REST API development while working with multiple frameworks, software, Operating systems and programming languages. Detail oriented, and highly effective at managing short and long-term projects for current, new, and emerging technologies, with a focus on solving problems that benefit stakeholders.

COMPETENT SKILLS

- Software Development
- Project Management
- Database Design & Management
- Troubleshooting & Debugging
- API Design & Algorithms
- Enterprise Implementations
- Software Development Lifecycle
- Release Management
- Team Building & Leadership
- Advanced Critical Thinking
- Communication Skills
- Customer Service

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript	Angular	SQL
Python	Drupal/WordPress	C#
.NET	Gatsby	Docker
React	REST/GraphQL	Bash

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

CapTech Consulting; Richmond, VA

Full-Stack Engineer - State Workers' Compensation

Aug 2018 - Present

March 2020 - Present

- Developed REST APIs with .NET Core 3.1 / Entity Framework for Angular 9 application
- Wrote test plans for coded enhancements and provided mentorship and feedback for Junior Developers

Full-Stack Engineer - State Entity

Dec 2019 - March 2020

 Rewrote Microsoft ASP.NET web application with Kentico CMS. Designed, debugged, and documented C#, HTML, CSS, and SQL

Full-Stack Engineer - See Kids Dream

Jun 2019 - Feb 2020

- Replaced monolithic WordPress solution with Headless WordPress, Gatsby, and GitLab-CI. Managed and reviewed work of Junior Developers
- Provided technical advice and assisted in solving programming problems. Involved with bug fixing on functionality, performance and designing issues with JavaScript, HTML5, and React

Software Engineer – Fortune 500 Company

Sep 2018 – Jan 2019

- Built data pipeline in Python that created and stored Time Series models for products in 10,000+ stores. Highly scalable and outperformed current moving average model
- Developed a wide range of functional enhancements and performance improvements to dozens of existing modules
 Now You See It: New York, NY
 Jun 2015 Present

Creator

- Manage YouTube channel with over 50 million total views and 800,000 subscribers. Analyze various film techniques with a small team of editors and designers
- Collaborate with diverse programming teams to prototype and solve complex business problems

University of Virginia; Charlottesville, VA

Jan 2016 - May 2018

Introduction to Python Teaching Assistant

Aided students in their Introduction to Computer Science class taught in Python. Led weekly Lab lessons to 35+ students
 American Red Cross; Richmond, VA
 Jun 2016 – Aug 2017

Database Architect

- Wrote SQL for nightly database inserts/updates to track 13,000+ daily blood donations in US. Built tables connecting relevant information from blood donation to blood drive databases
- Proposed new cleaning methods after finding unusual data patterns in over 50 million donors

EDUCATION

University of Virginia; Charlottesville, VA Bachelor of Arts in Computer

May 2014 - May 2018